all right so the question is should you
use books or should you just use a
documentation that comes with the
program um somebody asked a question so
I'm answering it it's a very easy one um
yes you should do both you should do
both you should use books and you should
use man page it's funny because there's
actually a very negative comment on one
of my YouTube videos I read recently
that said oh this is another one of
those Boomers is going to tell us to
just read the Man pages that come with
the system
I'm going to refrain from being negative
about this completely unemployed
mediocre doesn't finish watching the
video human being who made a comment on
my YouTube video hey there's a lot of
them and I will instead say that if you
are going to learn something you need to
figure out what it is you're going to
learn and then you need to Target the
learning resources that are best to
learn that
thing and that's it that's it I don't I
don't need to anything else right is it
a book let me let me tell you the
advantages of books over the stuff that
comes on the system okay the advantages
of a book um is that the book has
largely usually been edited right that
means that somebody has um there's
usually a single author one or two
people have authored it so you get a
common voice it's usually been edit
usually usually it's been edited I
actually did another video all about
that um why I used to stay away from
pack publishing versus O'Reilly blah
blah blah so you want to get a good book
usually as usual find if you've got a
mentor already right if you if you have
somebody who's in the industry and
you've already done the work which is
way way way way before you should be
asking whether you should read a book or
not you shouldn't be asking me that you
should be asking the person that you
found to be your mentor and that is
something you should have already done
right and and you might be using me as a
fill in for your Mentor for right now
but I'm telling you find a mentor who's
doing your job the job you want and then
ask them what do you think what do you
think is good is this book good is this
thing here good is is this video good is
this series good because they're going
to be the ones that are going to tell
you what learning resources to use and
that is really at the core of the
question the question isn't about
whether you should read from you know
the the Man pages and do web searches on
a given thing or should you read the
book The question is where is the best
place to learn the skills knowledge and
abilities for the specific targeted
career that I want Mr or Mrs Mentor you
know you're going to ask the person
not me right and it's going to depend
completely depending on on the on the
thing I'm not trying to to to dodge the
question I'm trying to tell you that it
makes sense I have one story about this
I've told a story before I'm going to
tell you this quick version of it so um
I went to a training for a
week I've did this video like I've did
this story like three times so I went to
training for a week so they PID $ 2500
$3,000 something like that horrible
training everybody got us gold star at
the end I went home and said never send
me to that again manager Barb I love
loved her she was great give me the
money instead went to Pal's books in
Portland bought all the books I ever
could want to study and learned from
those books having study Having learned
from my mentors that that those were the
books to get right and we're talking
about old school chin beard you know
brilliant Geniuses who dropped out of re
College who who had printed versions of
the Unix Man pages on their shelves and
and you know stupid YouTube commenters
who don't understand how to do
capitalization might make comments about
those people I would rather listen to
them and they said no that if you wanted
definitive resource on bash there is
nothing better than the bash man page
literally there there is not a single
book on planet Earth that covers
completion using the dash Capital C on
on bash it just does not exist I only
discovered it by reading The Bash man
page it is it does not exist anywhere
else so if you want a comprehensive
knowledge of a particular thing in the
case of bash you would go with the bash
man page on the system above any other
printed material and I've read like five
or six other books related to so yes
it's true that sometimes the the the
resource is going to be better um if
you're going to if you want to
understand tcpip you can read the
specification for tcpip and the rfc's
you learn to read specification separate
video about learning to read
specifications at some point I don't
know if that's necessarily going to fall
into the Boost we'll find out but
reading the specifications is is a
really good way to do that or you can
buy TCP IP Illustrated from Addison
Wesley which is the standard College
textbook to to learn learn tcpip but
it's extremely deep it's extremely low
level it tells you everything you want
to know about how a packet is formed
should you buy the book or should you go
read the spec probably both in that case
the point is is it depends and and
hopefully you have enough stories um uh
to do that hopefully I have enough
stories to know about how to go on that